Guide to the Daniele Varè \ Elizabeth Vincent Foster Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Daniele Varè / Elizabeth Vincent Foster collection
1918-1954
GEN MSS 481
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.26
(3 boxes)
A collection consisting principally of letters from Varè to Elizabeth Foster, who was married to Varè's nephew, Maxwell Foster. The letters cover Varè's various diplomatic assigments and his family life, leading up to, during, and after World War II. Also included are letters from other Varè family members to Foster, along with several third-party letters and materials related to the Varè family.
Varè, Daniele, 1880-1956
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase from Serendipity Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Other Foster family materials are in the Yale Collection of American Literature.
DANIEL VARè
Daniele Varè, Italian Minister to the Imperial Court in China, and diplomat, was the uncle of Maxwell Foster, a Yale alumnus and attorney, who married Elizabeth Vincent in 1927.
Scope and Contents
Series I, Letters from Daniele Varè to Elizabeth Vincent Foster makes up the bulk of this archive. Written between 1920 and 1954, the letters detail Varè's family life, his service as an Italian diplomat, and his concerns during World War II.
Series II, Other letters, contains many to Elizabeth Vincent Foster from other correspondents (principally Varè family members), and correspondence of others. Series III, Other Materials, includes printed copies of writings by Varè, calling cards, and photographs.
Diplomats -- Italy; Foster, Elizabeth Vincent; Varè, Daniele, 1880-1956
- Daniele Varè letters to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1920-1954, n.d.; Series I; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  - Letter, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
  - Letters, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Letters, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Letters, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letters, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Letters, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letters, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Letters, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Letters, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Letters, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Letters, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Letters, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Letters, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Letters, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Other Letters, 1919-1949; Series II; 0.21; (.5 box)
  - Aoyama, S.
    - to Maxwell and Elizabeth Foster, 1932 Dec 6 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bellinger, Alfred R.
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1927 Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brady, Agnes
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Champney, Kenneth
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1928 Sep 14 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Demby, James
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1926 Jul 7 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Dorothea"
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1931 Sep 27 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Morgan, Harry
    - to Maxwell Foster, 1925 Oct 13 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Neville"
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1927-28 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "V. P."
    - to unidentified, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Page, Thomas Nelson
    - Letter of introduction for George E. Vincent (as president of the Rockefeller Foundation), 1918 Apr 16 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes printouts of webpages re: Rockefeller Foundation
  - [Rowe, J.?]
    - to George E. Vincent, 1926 Jun 26 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Varè, Bettina
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Varè, Daniele
    - to "Gloriana", 1919 Oct 26 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - to Maxwell Foster, 1936 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - to Mrs. George E. Vincent, 1919 Oct 19 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Varè, Margherita
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1936, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Vincent, G. S.
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, [1919?] (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - "Walker"
    - to Mrs. George E. Vincent, 1919 Dec 20 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Win"
    - to Elizabeth Vincent Foster, 1936 Mar 24 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Unidentified
    - to unidentified, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Empty envelopes
    - to the Fosters, 1946, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - to the Varè family in care of the Fosters, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Other Material, Series III; 0.21; (.5 box)
  - Association Peritalia By-laws, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "British Foreign Policy through Italian Eyes" by Daniele Varè, offprint, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Calling cards from various persons, 1924, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Diary page listing Asian dynasties, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "The German Character", by Daniele Varè, printed version, Times, 1939 Oct 17 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Menu, signed by George E. Vincent and others, 1918 Apr 16 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Photographs of Varè family members, 1952, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Postcard: Juan-les-Pins, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Schedule: "Women's Broadcasts from Rome", 1939 Mar (Box 3, Folder 55)